I'm Joe.
>> I'm Jab.
>> Today we're gonna show you how to
install
>> Big Battery Ethos.
>> We have 10 of them installed here and 10
more that we're going to install right
here. Jab, what is that?
>> This is a 18 uh KB inverter EG4. First
thing you want to do is number all your
batteries. We have them numbered 1
through 10. [music] Then you have to set
the dip switches.
>> Dip switches are located on this side.
Before you mess with it, cut the BMS
off. Pink. And the manual shows you for
each number battery going from one all
the way up to 16 how you want to set the
dip switches. So we're going to just
follow what's shown here. So this is
number 10. So we're going to follow
number 10 on here.
>> What you [music] got?
>> So we have
>> 10. 10 is one up three up. One up
[music] three up. Now you confirm that
it's right. Is that correct?
>> Yes. Yes, that's correct.
>> All right. Number 10 is right,
>> dude. Hey, it's harder than it looks.
Yeah, cuz it's disorienting cuz you're
looking at [laughter] it.
>> It's tough. Hey,
>> you know, if you mess it up,
>> put them back on. Yeah. If you mess them
up, you got to take them all back down.
So, that's number 10. Now, where's
number 10 going to be in our sequence?
>> Well, number 10 is
>> So, number 10 is going to be down here.
>> So, we'll go ahead and stack it in
there.
>> Yep. And then we'll keep that way we get
them out of the way.
>> Now, I'm going to do number nine next.
Hold on. I remember this from last time.
We need to put the comm wire in there.
>> BMS. We need to turn it on either.
>> It's easy to forget. Even for real
professionals like us.
>> This is on with the green lights are on,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, BMS is on
>> and we need to get that long comm wire
>> at the bottom of Uh-huh.
>> This one, right?
>> Let's see. Now, hey, one other thing we
learned is that there's one of these
that is shorter than the other ones.
>> This one looks a little bit shorter.
>> Whoa, dude. Guess how we found that out?
By putting in a whole rack of batteries,
then it wouldn't reach.
>> There you go.
>> Yeah. [music]
>> Yeah. Just set that one. Set that. I
won't be able to find it now.
>> Well, I won't. [laughter]
>> This is number nine. BNS [music] off.
Look on my chart right here. Number
nine. One [music] up, four up. They all
come preset down.
So, [music] just move two up. Switch is
on. Right.
That BMS is on.
>> Yes.
>> BMS 10 on. BMS 9 on.
Set. Let me just set you in on there.
Slide her in there. Get it.
>> Got BMS on.
>> I got the nine on. You got clip her in
there. [music] This is number eight.
BMS off.
BMS number eight. One up, rest down.
Screwdriver
clip
screw.
BMS 8 is on. Always recommend making one
of these. It really helps, don't it,
Jab?
>> Yep. [laughter]
[music] How many did we have to take
down last time? Like two.
>> We had to before you know BMS off.
>> Oh, it was more than two.
>> That really helps us.
>> Big facts. Make a list. Nothing goes on
the bottom port of your first battery.
You can just take this cover and screw
it on there so nothing gets in. But
there is no comm in because this is the
last battery in the sink lens. So this
is number
seven. All right. Yeah. What? Check the
front. Make sure that's number seven.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> What do we got for seven? [music]
>> We got uh
>> So, seven 23 4 up. And you check to make
sure it's right.
>> 2 3 4.
>> Wait. No, no, no, no, no. Wait. Oh, I
was looking at the wrong one. You're
right. 2 3 4 up. Right.
>> Make sure I'm right.
>> I was looking at 13.
>> I It is confusing. If you just read this
manual and didn't have somebody
highlight this for you, [music] you'd
miss it,
>> right?
>> Cuz that's all it is. cuz it really
doesn't mention much about it for the
dips. [music]
It's just this one little section, but
crucially important.
>> I see
BMS off. That's set. All right, go mark
us off. Seven.
>> BMS on.
>> So, this this long one goes off the top
of seven.
>> Correct. We're going to come from seven
and go down to the bottom and hit number
six right there.
>> Man, I'll be honest with you, too. After
installing a bunch of different systems,
this one is the most complex, but also
one of the easiest to install if you
read all the directions.
>> Yeah. You have to understand. You have
to have an understanding, [music]
>> bro. But I have never in my life put a
system in brand new and it just worked
the first time.
>> Yeah.
>> Like there's always something.
>> We're going to continue down the
sequence from 10 to one, changing all
the dips on the battery. Is that it?
Double check. And that's for number
what?
>> Six.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. Number six. Now BMS on. Go cross
off number six. We have to connect
number six to number seven using that
bottom port and the long green cable.
Going to connect the weatherproof
connector in the bottom comp port here.
Then the quick connect in the top port
of battery 7.
Now we're connecting number six to
number seven with this long wire.
>> Number three.
>> Dang it. Sometimes this is the hardest
part.
>> Now you know why they put covers on the
back.
>> Cuz I'm trying not to freaking crush my
>> pinch. Pinch your hand.
>> You got it connected. Let's strap this
up.
>> Hey, that was quick. Man, that was
quick.
>> I told you to.
>> Hey, once you know how the system works,
we're not going to have them. Now, you
also know in your head if you ever you
ever needed to add some more batteries.
>> Yep. Or if any of them give me any
issues, I need to take them out. I know
how to do
>> exactly how.
>> It'll be a little bit of a pain to get a
fourth one up by myself. But I have to
figure it I figure it out there.
>> So, we got to change these dips.
>> What is this? Number two.
>> Number two.
>> Three. Three [music] up.
>> Just three.
>> Double check. Go ahead. You can double
check it.
>> That's number three. It's three.
>> No, number two.
>> Oh, number two.
>> See, it's confusing cuz it's number two
is three up,
>> right? [laughter]
>> Kobe, you cross off number two. BMS2
[music] on. There you go. So, these
connectors are two-part. That's the
water jacket right there. Then this goes
down to hold it in. [music] And that
that has another grommet in there that
threads down over the top of it to hold
it in place. Fits onto is on. Just slide
around there.
>> Can we put these back back on?
>> Mhm. Hey, notice Jeb, I want you to see
everything here is IP rated. You see
that gasket?
>> Yeah.
>> So, IP rated, weather resistant. Um,
these probably could be under a little
tent or something and would be just
fine.
>> Look what I have out there. Feels a
little
>> Only thing you probably run into is
humidity issues, but that's why we're
going to put a vent fan on here.
>> Question. Since these have a BMS,
[music]
these could be run down below the 10%
threshold without damage to themselves.
[music]
>> The BMS is going to stop.
>> So, it literally won't just
>> Right. It'll it'll shut it off. It'll go
into standby mode. So, in standby mode,
there will be
>> So, when I'm running my machine, this
will never happen cuz we have the
panels, but in theory, if it was a rainy
day, I could run it until it literally
just cuts off.
>> Yeah.
Oh yeah.
>> The other thing you can do is with this
generator backup right here, you can
have a gas generator to come in here and
charge these batteries if you're on the
road and don't have the solar going. Or
I [music] believe we could probably dude
we could put a red arc in and run the
extra charge off your alternator in here
to your bats.
>> And can this take 120 and 240 220 in?
>> I'm looking at only 240 right now.
That's why I was saying I have those 120
wall chargers that we can slap on there
and it'll charge directly. So, you could
really do it from anything. And homie,
with that charge controller, [music]
that Victron charge controller or with
that other charge controller, we could
have outputs you could plug wind
turbines in or water turbines. And like,
if you think about it, you're near a
river. You just take a water turbine and
throw it in there and run a wire back
and clip it in a tube. So, I'm going to
make this thing, you know, to where you
can really use it for for anything. And
I'm pretty sure I got it planned out
[music] now, but it's going to be really
easy to add and tweak. Once you see that
voltage converter go in and all that,
you'll be like, "Fuck." Last one.
This is the control panel. On the back,
there are extra battery ports that we're
not going to use. So, I just left the
covers on them. And then we have one for
the battery BMS and then one to
communicate with the inverter.
>> The green goes to the battery, correct?
>> Yes, sir. So, that goes from the
inverter. Let's feed it this way. Feed
me that in.
>> Do you want it from the top?
>> Hold on. Is this the same? We can use
these for the inverter. Look, you want
to know how I know this goes from the
battery to the inverter. Oh
>> yeah.
>> One of the things I tried when it
wouldn't work was swapping the cord
around. I was like, "Well, maybe that
side has to go on the battery. Maybe
that side has to go on the inverter."
Hold on.
>> Got it.
>> Got it. [music]
>> Okay. Got the other end. Got yours
plugged in.
>> About to All right. Mine's plugged in.
>> All right. We take the other end. Notice
I have ROMX connectors in here.
and
connect it right here where it says
batcom. These are the temp cords we had
up for testing. I'm going to take them
down and run some longer ones that look
better and are properly secured. Next,
you got to clip in the batteries. You
have the orange one that goes from
positive to positive and the black one
that goes from negative to negative. You
must make sure they click all the way.
Now, listen. There's two little clicks.
See [music] that one? Not all the way
clicked. Jeff, go ahead and tell them
the last one. Which one? Cuz look,
>> we're going to be going up to these top
ports [music] here cuz these ports are
going to be the points that end up going
to our bus bar.
>> And you can tell cuz these [music] line
up pretty perfect, don't they?
>> Sure do.
>> There we go.
>> Take and [music] run this under them.
Connect it to our negative. I can't do
it without a bucket. But a bucket is a
great insulator, by the way. You know
what else is a great insulator? Rainbow
Sandals.
>> Have they sponsored you yet?
>> No. I should just make my own
sandals.
>> Yeah, that was the thought of um of
Jabaroma. I'll promote it.
>> Hey Jab, if we had Hey, dude. If you
called them black neck, them
sell like hell. [laughter]
>> Yeah. When you say black neck feel like
hot. When I say redneck, they're like,
"Yeah."
>> Yeah, right.
>> At least I own it. If Joe Dur was a real
person, I'm in the front.
>> Your name is Joe, too? [music]
>> I'm telling you. So, then we're going to
connect. Pop that on our positive.
Connect that one back.
All right. Now, to connect
the inverter, we're going to run this
one from the negative side.
>> Hey, Jab. You think this is Imagine I'm
designing a power station for a boat.
You know, that's going to have to be top
of the line if something goes wrong on a
boat.
>> Bring it up. Now, bring it up. This same
[music] one here.
Go ahead and
>> that's all I need there.
>> Yep. We reach
>> wrap it. That just that's going to do
it. So, we don't need to cut any cuz any
other slack we could get a little bit
around here.
>> I want to take these like that and wrap
top.
>> If that's the case and we
>> just a hair and and you're right cuz
that that [music] needs to turn and then
we have if you ever have one turn like
that, you want to strap it right [music]
here. If not, it's going to want to
break on that seam. Okay.
There's the final bug up here. And I'm
going to take the red wire, connect it
to the battery terminal here,
crank her down.
All right, moment of truth, Jeff. What
we about to do? All right, so what we
have here is a solar trailer. 100
kilowatt hours of battery capacity
within this trailer. two 18KW inverters,
EG4, big battery, hooked us up with the
batteries, Ethos batteries, and we're
about to hook this on. Joe and I, we've
been busy at work. It's more auddle. And
we're going to uh we did all the wiring,
have everything hooked up. We're going
to turn it on for [music] the first time
live.
>> Last thing, we got to cut all them on,
do our final checks, make sure they're
clipped in, and cut them breakers on.
>> Yep.
All of them on too, man. Like as far as
the connector, we missing on this time
the first time.
>> Yeah.
>> It's a learning experience.
>> All right. So, we just have this this
battery controller here.
>> Go ahead and cut that one. Ready? One,
two, three.
>> Got them.
>> Hold on. Now, touch it one time and
wait. Does it come on?
>> We got lights up here.
>> I have lights.
>> This battery controller.
>> All right, Je.
>> So, now it's the inverter.
>> You do the honor, my man. Hit that on
and we should get a light up here
>> or blow up. [laughter]
Hey, hold on. Now we have a light. Do we
have any warnings? Do we have any
faults? We should have the AC uh the
trip by no AC. [music]
>> What we doing there?
>> Oh, now we got a notice. Now that should
be trip by no AC. So we come [music]
over here. Alarm status. Trip by no AC.
Okay. Advanced. All right. Run without
grid. You have to select password. What
is it? [music] Zer. All zeros.
>> All right. So then you have to hit it
again. And then you have to hit set a
couple times. Oh,
>> no warning.
>> No warning.
>> And we're active
>> now. Where's the meter?
>> Dude, I got you one of these, too.
They're my favorite one, bro.
>> Auto detect.
>> Put on the mode, right?
>> And we should see 230.
>> 2, baby.
>> First time. First try.
>> 240. And that's
>> that's all of it.
>> That's all of it.
>> Let's try the other one. Just make sure
it works.
>> 240.
>> We have output. All right. Guess what?
>> Second [music] try was a charm. The
first time a little work now homie we
are to the AC part. The power production
part's done. Now what [music] we have to
do is connect the comm wires from both
inverters and then the outputs of both
inverters to our combiner box. This is a
dedicated one that I have. We're going
to take the outputs of both inverters
and wire them in here on a 50 amp
breaker and then come out of here with
the mains and go straight out of there
and [music] wire into another regular
panel for 240. That way you'll have 100
amps at 240 in a regular house panel and
from there we'll put all your
accessories on, bro. But the hard part
is done.
>> Yeah, good stuff.
>> Let's go save planet Earth or some
dog.